William R. Ratchford Papers 1984.0021
Archives and Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Library
- Series VI: Committee Files, 1979 - 1985
  - House Administration Committee, 1979 - 1980 (Box 80)
    - National publications act, 1979, H.R. 5424
    - New members orientation, (3 folders)
    - New members orientation, (2 folders) (Box 82)
    - Obey, railback, 1979
    - Office account, equipment relief regulations
    - Official act amendments, 1979
    - Public financing, (20 folders)
    - Public printing act, 1979, H.R. 4572
    - Shroeder, Pat
    - Smithsonian, south garden, (2 folders)
    - Task force on enforcement, (2 folders)
    - Vietnam memorial
  - House Appropriations
    - Interior Appropriations Committee (Box 83-84)
      - Appropriations correspondence
      - Interior appropriations correspondence (Box 85)
      - Interior appropriations subject files (Box 86)
      - Appropriations committee, 1983-1985 (Box 87)
      - Interior department budget justifications (Box 88)
      - Interior agencies hearing transcripts, 1983 February - 1984 May (Box 89-94)
    - Transportation Committee (Box 95-99)
      - Transportation hearings transcripts, 1983 March - 1984 April
      - Transportation printed documents (Box 100)
  - Environment, Energy, and Natural Resources Committee, 1979 - 1981 (Box 101)
    - Capital cost recovery act, H.R. 4646
    - Clear air/acid raing
    - Chloroflorocarbon briefing packet
    - Colorado River plan
    - Department of natural resources
    - Environment
    - Environmental contaminents in food
    - Export administration act
    - Fishing rights, Washington state
    - Fish and wildlife conservation act
    - George Bank issue
    - Import of Russian watches
    - Land use planning wilderness
    - Law of the sea treaty
    - Lincoln Derby hydroelectric project
    - Oceanic and atmospheric affairs
    - Offshore fishing limits
    - Rare II
    - Recycling, bottle bill
    - Resourses conservation act
    - Tax treatment of Americans working overseas
    - Water resources
    - Wilderness program
    - Wildlife
- Series VII: Issue Mail, 1979 - 1984
  - Text Summary and Form Responses [outgoing] (Box 102)
    - Text Summary 1 - 35009 [outgoing]
    - ROBO Form Responses [incoming]
      - 1 - 21857
      - 22022 - 32757 (Box 103)
      - 9070 - 32320
  - Master Directory, 1979-1984
    - A - Le, (6 folders) (Box 103a)
    - Le - Z, (6 folders) (Box 103b)
  - Correspondence and Attachments [incoming]
    - Document number
      - 1 - 2950, 1979 (Box 104)
      - 2950 - 5450, 1979 (Box 105)
      - 5451 - 7450, 1979-1980 (Box 106)
      - 7451 - 9750, 1979-1980 (Box 107)
      - 9751 - 11650, 1979-1981 (Box 108)
      - 11651 - 13750, 1980-1981 (Box 109)
      - 13751 - 16750, 1980-1981 (Box 110)
      - 16751 - 19300, 1981 (Box 111)
      - 19301 - 21250, 1981 (Box 112)
      - 21251 - 25200, 1981-1982 (Box 113)
      - 25201 - 31100, 1982 (Box 114)
      - 31101 - 32150, 1982 (Box 115)
      - 32151 - 40450, 1982 (Box 116)
      - 40451 - 46850, 1982-1983 (Box 117)
      - 46851 - 54199, 1982-1983 (Box 118)
      - 54200 - 57400, 1983 (Box 119)
      - 57401 - 63900, 1983-1984 (Box 120)
      - 63901 - 65400, 1983-1984 (Box 121)
    - Attachments
      - 1 - 3299, 1979-1980 (Box 122)
      - 3300 - 7099, 1979-1980 (Box 123)
      - 7100 - 9699, 1979-1980 (Box 124)
      - 9700 - 12599, 1979-1981 (Box 125)
      - 12600 - 18499, 1980-1981 (Box 126)
      - 18500 - 23199, 1981-1982 (Box 127)
      - 23200 - 29599, 1981-82 (Box 128)
      - 29600 - 33299, 1982 (Box 129)
      - 33300 - 39999, 1982 (Box 130)
      - 40000 - 43299, 1982 (Box 131)
      - 43300 - 48699, 1982-1983 (Box 132)
      - 48700 - 54499, 1983 (Box 133)
      - 54500 - 71699, 1983 (Box 134)
      - 71700 - 71699, 1983-1984 (Box 135)
      - 71700 - 76099, 1983-1984 (Box 136)
      - 76100 - 77199, 1983-1984 (Box 137)
      - 77200 - 77499, and assorted, 1983-1984 (Box 138)
      - 73860 - 79857, 1983 (Box 139)
      - 75900 - 77499, 1983-1984 (Box 140)
      - 1984 correspondence (microfiche)
- Series VIII: Political Files, 1978 - 1984
  - 1978-1982 Campaigns
    - Political pamphlets (Box 141)
    - Campaign computer program
    - Coordinators meeting, 1981 August 30
    - Dodd canvas, 1980
    - Census information, 1980
    - Correspondence, 1981
    - Campaign materials
    - Labor lists
    - Congressional coordinators list
    - The majority party
    - Dodd targeting, 1980
    - FEC advisory opinions
    - U.S. chamber of commerce
    - 5th district town chairmen
    - Presidential delegate selection, 1980
    - 5th democratic state central names
    - 5th mayors and selectmen
    - Defense spending, Connecticut
    - MX dense pact
    - NCEC new members seminar
    - DCCC incumbant assitance task force
    - 1982 postal rates
    - Vote ratings for Bill, 1981-1982
    - Candidate Robert O'Brien
    - Neal Hanlon background materials
    - NCPAC information
    - 1982 campaign
    - Speech cards
    - Photographs, (2 folders)
    - Cable tv rates
    - Leventhal, Bob
    - Jewish PAC mailing
    - 1984 endorsements to Bill
    - Newspaper article on Bill
    - Euromissles (Box 142)
    - Monthly expenditure reports
    - Peter, Paul and Mary
    - Correspondence
    - Campaign material
    - Master file
    - Slone political correspondence
    - O'Neil solicitation
    - Jewish lists
    - Old campaign material, (2 folders)
    - Miscellaneous election results
    - Resumes campaign
    - Issue flatsheets, 1978
    - Issue flatsheets, 1980
    - Issue flatsheets, 1982
    - Political Action Committee, (2 folders)
    - Subject Files (Box 143)
      - Aging
      - Budget
      - Defense
      - Education
      - Employment
      - Environment/nuclear
      - Flood
      - Housing
      - Israel, Poland, El Salvador
      - Transportation
      - Veterans
      - Women's issues
      - Democrates, other races
      - 5th district nominating convention
      - News releases, 1982
      - Republicans
      - Republicans, pre-convention
      - Donahue, Edward
      - Hanlon, Neal
      - Moffett, Toby
      - O'Neil, William
      - Ratchford, William, (5 folders)
      - Reagan, Ronald
    - A report on a poll conducted in the 5th congressional district of Connecticut, 1982 February (Box 144)
    - A survey of voter attitudes and opinions, 1978 March
    - A survey of voter attitudes and opinions, 1978 October
    - A trend survey of voter attitudes and opinions, 1978 August
    - A trend survey of voter attitudes and opinions, 1978 October
    - Analysis of Beacon Falls, 1982 (Box 145)
    - Campaign budget, 1982
    - Field plans, 1982
    - Percentage Ratchford favorability and contacts
    - Phonebank trend reports
    - Ratchford, Bill, 1982 October
    - Targeting, 1982 August
    - A trend survey of voter attitudes and opinions, 1982 August
    - DSG campaign fund survey, 1982 July (Box 146)
    - DSG campaign fund survey, 1982 October
    - Ratchford report
    - Billboards
    - Landpower issues, 1984 (Box 147)
    - Midgetman
    - Comprehensive test ban treaty
    - Defense economic adjustment act
    - INF talks
    - Background on Pershing/cruise missile
    - Incremental freeze arms race moratorium act
    - MX missle, technical data/arguments
    - MX floor statements
    - Nerve gas amendment
    - Weapon system data
    - Space weapons
    - MX dear colleagues
    - MX (H.R. 113, release of funds)
    - Freeze lobby effors
    - FY 85 defense budget materials
    - Countdown Connecticut
    - Nuclear freeze information
    - Scowcraft final report
    - Freeze floor specific
    - Volunteer army
    - Defense standing
    - Aircraft carrier survivability
    - R and D facility at Avery Point in Groton
    - Salt II
    - Civil defense
    - Maybank amendment, procurement
    - Correspondence (2 folders), 1984 December -1985 March
    - Political broadcasting information, (2 folders) (Box 148)
    - Radio timecard rates, (2 folders)
    - Library
    - Fundraising, 1984
    - Campaign debates, 1984
    - First poll, 1984
    - Contribution lists (Box 149)
    - Mailing lists, 1983
    - A report on a tracking survey 5th congressional district
      - 1984 August
      - 1984 September
      - 1984 October
    - A survey of attitudes, 1984 February
    - A survey of voter attitudes in Connecticut's 5th congressional district, 1984 February
    - Election surveys - Ratchford (Box 150)
      - 1984 August
      - 1984 October 15
      - 1984 October 22 - 23
      - 1984 November 1
  - Campaign Releases (Box 151)
    - Waterbury supporters host Ratchford fundraiser, 1980 April 3
    - Ratchford to announce re-election plans, 1980 June 3
    - Announcement of candidacy speech, 1980 June 9
    - Ratchford names campaign leaders, 1980 June 19
    - Ratchford to open campaign headquarters, 1980 June 23
    - Ratchford plans fundraiser, 1980 July 3
    - Ratchford plans fundraiser cruise, 1980 July 3
    - Ratchford names benefit cruise committee, 1980 July 10
    - Ratchford discloses FEC financial report, 1980 July 10
    - Convention advisory, 1980 July 14
    - Ratchford names coordinator, 1980 July 15
    - Ratchford nominated for second term, 1980 July 24
    - Ratchford names coordinator, 1980 July 25
    - Ratchford district schedule, 1980 August 1
    - Meridan men display paintings, 1980 August 5
    - Ratchford holds "family outing", 1980 August 5
    - Ratchford district schedule, 1980 August 8
    - 2nd annual "Ratchford night" planned, 1980 August 14
    - Ratchford to open Waterbury campaign headquarters, 1980 August 18
    - Editor's advisory, 1980 October 6
    - Ratchford's district schedule, 1980 October 9
    - Ratchford's district schedule, 1980 October 16
    - Ratchford releases financial report, 1980 October 18
    - Singer to perform for Ratchford, 1980 October 22
    - O'Neil to stump for Ratchford, 1980 October 21
    - Claude Pepper to tour district, 1980 October 25
    - Ratchford election day advance, 1980 October 27
    - Ratchford district schedule, 1980 October 27
    - Ratchford attacks Reagan economic proposal, 1980 September 20
    - Ratchford district schedule, 1980 September 24
    - State representative to host coffee hour for Ratchford, 1980 September 30
    - October editor's advisory, 1980 October 1
    - Ratchford press releases 1978 campaign
    - Towns, (19 folders)
    - Guidera, George, (2 folders) (Box 152)
    - Sarasin issues
    - Grasso, literature
    - Guidera issues
    - Fund raising letters
    - Completed issues outlines
    - Polls
    - Ratchford, campaign literature
    - Ratchford, speeches
    - Energy
    - All past issues, 1974-1977
    - DNC and FEC materials
    - Towns, (7 folders)
      - Town maps
      - Delegate lists
      - Committee lists
    - Voter registration
    - Organization
    - Mailing envelopes
- Series IX: Casework Files, 1979 - 1984
  - Alden Weir farm preservation (Box 153)
  - Ansonia technical assistance
  - Atlantic-Johnson metal house
  - The Barden Corporation - military flyover
  - Beacon Falls
    - Chemical wastes
    - PCB storage
  - Beaver Brook flooding
  - Beryl Corporation
    - Import markers
    - Import pens
    - Pencil tariff case
  - Better Formed Metals of Waterbury - EPA
  - Biaggi, Mario/fuel assistance
  - Branson Equipment - export relicense application
  - Branson Sonic Power/E star award
  - Briston Babcock
    - EPA sewer grant contract
    - Export license application
    - Product classifications
  - Canberrou Industries of Meriden
  - Cranberry export licences
  - Capone, John - Sec 8 in Hamden
  - Carey Industries, Inc. - Danbury
  - Century Brass
  - Century Brass - Waterbury
  - Cheshire Ball and Socket Co.
  - Cheshire Hillside Village
  - Coccomo, Thomas A., Memorial Health Care Center
  - Colt Chandler Evans Copperhead Missile
  - Commode Hull Bridge rehabilitation
  - Community Research Applications, Inc.
  - ConDiesel/Ribbon Bridge, U.S. State Dept.
  - Conoptics, Inc. International Trade Administration
  - Copper, Import restrictions on
  - Danbury
    - Airport
    - Data Control Systems
    - Drinking water problems
    - Chamber of Commerce, Greater
    - Health Plan, Greater
    - Intercultural Association, Greater
    - Sewers
  - Datahr of Danbury (HUD)
  - Derby vs Army Corp of Engineers
  - Derby
    - Census figures
    - Court case, flood program
  - Derby SBA
  - Design Circuits of Danbury
  - DOD appropriations, Perkin - Elmer
  - Fairmont Heights project
  - Farrel/Exim Bank
  - Farrel Company
    - Shipping and exports
    - Watervlei Arsenal
  - Federal Correctional Institution, Danbury
  - Fialou, Dennison F., congressional candidate
  - Flagg Co., DOE Construction
  - Footwear Industries of America
  - Freeman vs Mitchell
  - GAO - Doto contract
  - General Data Comp.
  - General Services Administration
  - Hanahoe Clinic
  - Hannan, Robert
  - Hartford hearing
  - Hearst, Sheldon - Wilton (Supermarket)
  - Hebrew Home of Hartford AOA proposal
  - Hewitt Manor
    - Elderly housing
    - Proposal for Shelton
  - Heyman, Sam - Stamford postal facility
  - Housatonic Flood Co. - Shelton
  - Hull Dye (Box 154)
  - International Creative Data Industries, Inc.
  - International Union (UAW)
  - Ives Street firehouse
  - Jacobson, David
  - Kasper Association: GBTD UMTA contract
  - The Kelsey Co. of Meriden
  - Kerile Co.
  - Kramer, Jack - FEC
  - Latex Foam Products, Inc.
  - Lewis Corporation
    - Ultrasonic cleaning equipment
  - Little, Officer Onofrio J.
  - Lloyd Lumber - EPA suspension ODR
  - Lone Star Industries
  - Man Barrier Corp., (2 folders)
  - Marou, Annette - sodium vapor lights
  - Mattatuck cooperative education grant
  - McHugh, Ray
    - Elderly housing project
    - Sec 8 - WTBY
  - Medallic Art Co.
  - Meriden
  - Meriden
    - Elderly housing sec. 8
    - Fotomat
    - Glen Hills area flooding
    - Markham airport
    - Photomat Corporation
  - Metz, Sonny, Union of Operation Engineers
  - Moschello and Motamed case
  - Moskof, Howard
  - Municipal emergency fuel programs
  - National Distilleries Corp.
  - New Canaan
  - New Medico/Medic and Ramb
  - Nicklebery, Asher - Sec 8 housing
  - North end of Waterbury project area
  - Oblon, Joyce
  - Olin Corp/UDAC grant, New Haven
  - O'Sullivan Island, Derby
  - EPA superfun cleanup
  - Palmer, Donald
  - Parson Real Estate/Naugatuck
  - Papazozloou, George/FAA report
  - Peterson, Dr. Scott/optometry
  - Pitney Bowes
  - Pitney Bowes - Commerce Park traffic problems
  - Pryor, Judge William C.
  - Rapco Foam
  - Reagonomics
  - Redding open spaces
  - Ridgefield Gilbert Foundation
  - Ridgefield urban system
  - Rust, Richard - Danbury Hat Co.
  - Satter, Judge Robert
  - Savings Tower
  - Shelton - Richardson/Merrill/EPA/Bridge
  - Silbert, Jean case
  - Sikorsky Aircraft
  - Small Business Administration
  - Supplemental Food Stamp Petition
  - Taube, Dr. Sheila
  - Teamster contract Shelton
  - Title XIX sheltered workshop
  - Extension of Tmago Waivers
  - Tmo Industries
  - TRA - Fartel Division - USM
  - Trumbull Lake project - public works committee
  - Trumbull post office
  - Union Carbide
  - Union Manufacturing
  - Urban Systems Project - Ridgefield
  - Utility Contractors Association of Connecticut
  - Valley EDA revolving loan fund (Box 155)
  - Vetrans appeal case of Peter Matavenda
  - Waco Properties/Brownstein Case
  - Waterbury
    - Association, housing
    - Building Trade Council
    - Farrel Division of Textron Inc.
    - Health Screening
    - Housing Authority
    - Mettatuck/Arrowhead MFG
    - Revenue
    - Urban grant
  - Wells Benus pension benefit
  - Westport
  - White, Barry - CT Aging Department conflict
  - Whitemore, Lynn/DOD request
  - Widder Corp., (2 folders)
  - Winokur Water Systems - Navy
  - Winn Developers of Waterbury
  - X-Med/O'Neil case
  - Yankee Telecommunications project
  - Young, Charter apartments
  - Zwinn, Stephen, elderly employment program proposal
- Series X: Ratchford Journal, 1979 - 1986
  - Ratchford Journal, 1979-1986 (Box 155)
- Series XI: Newspaper Clippings, 1979 - 1982
  - Newspaper clippings, 1979-1982 (Box 156-61)
- Series XII: Audio and Visual Recordings, 1979 - 1984
  - Video Tapes (Box 162)
    - The Ratchford Report
      - with Congressman Thomas Foley, House Majority Whip, 1983 May 4
      - with Richard Gephardt, 1983 June 5
      - with Representative Sidney Yates, Chairman Interior Appropriations Committee, 1983 July 28
      - 1983 November 9
      - 1983 December 7
      - with Representative Barbara Kennelly, 1984 January 3
      - with Representative Geraldine Ferraro, 1984 March 8 (Box 163)
      - 1984 April 11
    - American Debate, Representative William Ratchford, D-CT, vs Dr. Garrey Carruthers, Assistant of the Interior for Land and Water Resources: Mineral Leasing on Public Land [Roosevelt Center for American Studies, 30 mins.], 1983 May 19 (Box 164)
    - Portrait of America: Connecticut [Turner Educational Services, 49 mins.], undated
    - Ratchford-Rowland debate "By-Line", undated
    - Representative John Rowland, undated
    - Team annual meeting, 1984; (7 mins.)
  - Movie Film (Box 165)
    - Congressman Ratchford "Act of Congress", (3 reels)
    - Congressman Ratchford "Beauty Shots", 1984 October 3
  - Audio Recording Tape
    - O'Neil, Danbury, 1980 October 24
    - Radio spots
      - Independence: Performance: delivering, undated
      - Jobs revisited, 1984 October 19
      - Taxes; Fairness, Neal Hanlon, undated
      - Testimonial; People who know him best; Medicare Unemployment; Heat; Fairness; Neal Hanlon; Difference; Everybody else, 1982
    - Ratchford, undated
    - Ratchford for Congress
      - Delivering, undated
      - Jobs; TV voice over,:27.8, 1984 October 16
    - Ridgefield town meeting (parts 1&2), 1979 July 28
    - Tandem testimony, 1984 March 22
    - James Watts, 1983 May
    - Wilton/Weston/Westport town meeting, 1979 July 21
    - Air traffic, oil shortage, 1984 September (Box 166)
    - Comments on budget effect on employment in district, 1979 February 13
    - Disability reviews, acid rain, 1983 June 10
    - EPA funding, civil rights, 1983 June
    - Gas shortage, floor house speech on the elderly energy, congressional pay raise, 1979 May, June
    - Medicare, 1983 May
    - Nerve gas, agent orange, tandems, 1983 May, June
    - Q&A, 1983 May
    - Representative William Ratchford (3 tapes), 1980 January, 1982 June, 1983 February
    - Veterns, agent orange, health care for unemployed, 1983 March
    - Vet day, telephone charges, 1983 November
    - Tandem, 1984 February
    - Trampo bill, 1984 June
    - Ansonia, undated
    - CETA cutbacks, undated
    - Discussion of Ratchford mail rebates, undated
    - Federal loan program, oil price deregulation, reaction to Carter energy plan, undated
    - Institute of Water Resources with Dr. Carol Burke, undated
    - Oil shortage plan, undated
    - Ratchford for Congress, undated
    - Tandems, undated
    - Tandem truck concessions, budget, tax cap vote, undated
    - Trampo briefing, undated
    - Representative Ratchford, (13 tapes)
    - unidentified tapes, (7 tapes)
- Series XIII: Photographs and Memorabilia, 1961 - 1984
  - Photographs (Box 167)
    - Congressional sessions
    - Ratchford
      - portraits
      - with actors
      - with Homer Babbidge
      - with constitutents, (7 folders)
      - with family
      - with individuals
      - with interns
      - with political figures (Box 168)
      - with staff
    - Miscellaneous
    - Negatives (incomplete)
    - Slides
    - Ratchford, 1960s-1970s (Box 169)
    - Plaques, (12) (Box 170-71)
    - Certificates, (24) (Box 172)
    - Political Memorabilia (Box 173-74)
      - Cartoons
      - Posters
      - Framed certificates
      - License plate
      - Needlepoint
    - Scrapbooks, (2) (Box 175-76)
      - 1961-1972, 1978-1984